{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following is not a basic element within the microprocessor?", "opta": "Microcontroller", "optb": "Arithmetic logic unit (ALU)", "optc": "Register array", "optd": "Control unit", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which method bypasses the CPU for certain types of data transfer?", "opta": "Software interrupts", "optb": "Interrupt-driven I/O", "optc": "Polled I/O", "optd": "Direct memory access (DMA)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an enhancement to the Pentium that was unavailable in the 8086/8088?", "opta": "\"Pipelined\" architecture", "optb": "Expansion of cache memory", "optc": "Inclusion of an internal math coprocessor", "optd": "Data/address line multiplexing", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which bus is bidirectional?", "opta": "Address bus", "optb": "Control bus", "optc": "Data bus", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DMA is particularly suited for data transfer between the ________.", "opta": "disk drive and CPU", "optb": "disk drive and RAM", "optc": "disk drive and ROM", "optd": "disk drive and I/O", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first microprocessor had a(n)________.", "opta": "1-bit data bus", "optb": "2-bit data bus", "optc": "4-bit data bus", "optd": "8-bit data bus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which microprocessor has multiplexed data and address lines?", "opta": "8086/8088", "optb": "80286", "optc": "80386", "optd": "Pentium", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not an operand?", "opta": "Variable", "optb": "Register", "optc": "Memory location", "optd": "Assembler", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not part of the execution unit (EU)?", "opta": "Arithmetic logic unit (ALU)", "optb": "Clock", "optc": "General registers", "optd": "Flags", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 20-bit address bus can locate ________.", "opta": "1,048,576 locations", "optb": "2,097,152 locations", "optc": "4,194,304 locations", "optd": "8,388,608 locations", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is occurring when two or more sources of data attempt to use the same bus?", "opta": "Bus contention", "optb": "Direct memory access", "optc": "Bus interruption", "optd": "PPI", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a jump instruction?", "opta": "JB (jump back)", "optb": "JA (jump above)", "optc": "JO (jump if overflow)", "optd": "JMP (unconditional jump)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following was not a design improvement for the 8086/8088 over the 8085?", "opta": "Execution unit (EU)", "optb": "16-bit data bus", "optc": "Arithmetic logic unit (ALU)", "optd": "Bus interface unit (BIU)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Polled I/O works best when ________.", "opta": "there are no priority considerations", "optb": "priority considerations are frequent", "optc": "the polling rate exceeds 1000 s", "optd": "the polling rate is below 1000 s", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an arithmetic instruction?", "opta": "INC (increment)", "optb": "CMP (compare)", "optc": "DEC (decrement)", "optd": "ROL (rotate left)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During a read operation the CPU fetches ________.", "opta": "a program instruction", "optb": "another address", "optc": "data itself", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first Intel microprocessor to contain on-board cache memory was the ________.", "opta": "80386", "optb": "80486", "optc": "Pentium", "optd": "Pentium Pro", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an 8086/8088 general-purpose register?", "opta": "Code segment (CS)", "optb": "Data segment (DS)", "optc": "Stack segment (SS)", "optd": "Address segment (AS)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a computer bus?", "opta": "Data bus", "optb": "Control bus", "optc": "Timer bus", "optd": "Address bus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With interrupt-driven I/O, if two or more devices request service at the same time, ________.", "opta": "the device closest to the CPU gets priority", "optb": "the device that is fastest gets priority", "optc": "the device assigned the highest priority is serviced first", "optd": "the system is likely to crash", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Pentium can address ________.", "opta": "1 MB", "optb": "1 GB", "optc": "2 GB", "optd": "4 GB", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A port can be ________.", "opta": "strictly for input", "optb": "strictly for output", "optc": "bidirectional", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a computer functional block?", "opta": "Analog-to-digital converter", "optb": "Central-processing unit", "optc": "Memory", "optd": "Input/output ports", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Pentium microprocessor has a data bus of ________.", "opta": "16 bits", "optb": "32 bits", "optc": "64 bits", "optd": "128 bits", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The process of jointly establishing communication is called ________.", "opta": "DMA", "optb": "bidirectional addressing", "optc": "multiplexing", "optd": "handshaking", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}